Guide to the Kent Family Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V. Lecture Notes and Reading Notes, 1783-1860 and undated
  - Sub-Series V.1: Notes on the works of published single authors
    - Thomas, A.L., & Aguesseau, H.(1826). [Éloge de H. d'Aguesseau.] The Eulogy of D'Aguesseau, Chancellor of France, with historical illustrations. Translated from the French, etc. Cheltenham, in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Notes on the essays of Sir Benjamin Thompson, Count Rumford (1753 –1814), in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Voltaire,. (1728). La Henriade. [Ten cantos.]. London, in unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Voltaire,. (1759). An essay on universal history, the manners, and spirit of nations: From the reign of Charlemaign to the age of Lewis XIV. London: Printed for J. Nourse. unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Watteville, A. L. (1754). Histoire de la Confédération helvétique, par M. Alexandre Louis de Watteville. Se vend à Berne: chez Gottschall et c., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Whitaker, J. (1771). The history of Manchester: In four books. By John Whitaker. London: Sold by Mess. Dodsley in Pall-Mall, White and Lowndes, Payne, Cadell, Davis, Baker and Leigh, and Brotherton and Sewell; by Parker at Oxford, and Merrils at Cambridge; and by Newton, Clarke, and Harrop at Manchester., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Notes on the doctrine of feuds presumably from. An introduction to the law of tenures: By Martin Wright(1750 ), unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Young, A. (1893). A Tour in Ireland, 1776-1779 by Arthur Young. London-Paris-Melbourne: Cassell., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Sub-Series V.2: Notes on the Works of Published Multiple Authors
    - Notes on historical tracts, reading the classics and various philosophers from various unidentified authors and Basil Kenneth's "The Antiquities of Rome" (1767), James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Notes on the Roman Constitution taken chiefly from René-Aubert Vertot (1655-1735) and Livy. unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Notes on Voltaire's History of the War of 1741 (1756), Newton, and Adam Ferguson's "An Essay on the Hisory of Civil Society" (1767), unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Notes on Chemistry and Mineralogy taken from an encyclopedia, unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Sub-Series V.3: Notes by Subject
    - Notes on the Berlin and Milan Degrees, William Kent, 1846 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Notes on Aaron Burr, William Kent, 1855 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Notes on Chivalry, William Kent, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Notes on Domicil, William Kent, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Notes on Easement, William Kent, 1852 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Notes on the East India Company, James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Notes on the Geography of Hindoostan, James Kent, 1798 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Notes on Interpretation taken from Elementary principles of interpretation (Ernesti, 1842), William Kent, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Notes on Interpretation taken from Introduction to sacred philosophy and interpretation (Planck, 1834), William Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Notes on Interpretation taken from Institutes of natural law (Rutherforth, 1832), William Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Notes on Interpretation," William Kent, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - "Notes on the Doctrine of Interpretation," William Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Notes on the Law of Nations, William Kent, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Notes on Off-Shore Land, William Kent, 1845 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - "A Conversation on Religion," James Kent in the hand of Helen Kent (Mrs.William Kent), 1845 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Notes on Salvage, William Kent, 1846 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Notes on Wills, William Kent, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Sub-Series V.4: Public Addresses
    - Address to the Scotch Presbyterian Church, John Mitchell Mason, with notes by James Kent, 1810 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Address for the New England Anniversary Dinner, James Kent, 1834 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Sub-Series V.5: Poems in Manuscript
    - Lines from Wordsworth, in the hand of Anna Brownell Jameson, undated (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - "Beacon Side" and "Count Not the Hours" by unknown author, undated (Box 5, Folder 78)